<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-29T13:59:31-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Moscou Group at The Sainsbury Laboratory</title><subtitle>The Moscou group focuses on understanding immunity in the grasses. Current themes in our research include dissecting the genetic architecture of nonhost resistance, tradeoffs between biotrophs and necrotrophs, seedling versus adult plant resistance, and suppression of resistance in polyploid genomes. The group uses genetics and bioinformatics to explore biology and solve long-standing puzzles.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Analyzing, curating, and annotating bacterial artificial chromosome clones from complex genomes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/bac/pacbio/tutorial/2017/03/28/BAC_analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analyzing, curating, and annotating bacterial artificial chromosome clones from complex genomes" /><published>2017-03-28T07:40:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-28T07:40:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/bac/pacbio/tutorial/2017/03/28/BAC_analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/bac/pacbio/tutorial/2017/03/28/BAC_analysis.html">&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we explore current approaches at assembling, curating, and annotating bacterial artificial chromosomes (BACs) from complex genomes. We use an example from the &lt;i&gt;Mla&lt;/i&gt; locus in barley and discuss methodologies to annotate different biological information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several strategies exist for generating large sequence insert libraries including cosmid (Lambda phage cos sequence-based; 37-52 kb), fosmid (bacterial F-plasmid; up to 40 kb), bacterial artificial chromosomes (BACs; 150-350 kb), and yeast artificial chromsomes (YACs; 100-1000 kb). While YACs can contain the largest inserts, they have been dropped from use due to instability. Large insert libraries are the foundation of assembling genomes including the generation of minimal tiling paths (MTPs) and the characterization of complex loci (such as loci containing R genes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sequencing of large insert libraries traditional involved the subcloning of plasmids into smaller fragments with varying length, often with fragment sizes around 3 kb. Flanking sequence within the cloned fragments are subsequently sequenced using Sanger sequencing. A depth of approximately 10X was required for assembly of the BAC. Full assembly of BAC clones would be performed phred/phrap and CAP3 software that use an overlap-based approach for assembly. The quality of the assembly could be inferred by concordance of subcloned fragment size length with anchored 5’ and 3’ sequenced inserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant gains in long read sequencing such as PacBio permits the identification of a single contig in one SMRT sequencing run. This improvement can be attributed to the generation of long reads up to 30 kb. These reads take the place of subcloned fragments in traditional sequencing, whereas small reads are used for refinement of the sequence. While the HGAP assembly pipeline is extremely powerful, by default it will assume that the genome is linear rather than circular. A pipeline exists to deal with the problem, but manual curation can also be used. Below are some examples of sequenced BAC clones from the Mla7 locus from the barley cultivar CI 16153 that involve various types of assembly outputs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">In this tutorial we explore current approaches at assembling, curating, and annotating bacterial artificial chromosomes (BACs) from complex genomes. We use an example from the Mla locus in barley and discuss methodologies to annotate different biological information.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Moscou Group blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/general/2017/03/27/moscou-group-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Moscou Group blog" /><published>2017-03-27T09:54:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-27T09:54:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/general/2017/03/27/moscou-group-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/general/2017/03/27/moscou-group-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;Our research group blog is now online. We hope to provide updates on ongoing research projects, journal club selections, software development, upcoming presentations, and outreach activities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Our research group blog is now online. We hope to provide updates on ongoing research projects, journal club selections, software development, upcoming presentations, and outreach activities.</summary></entry></feed>